American Montessori Society Records 2006.0230
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series XXII: Sound Recordings, undated, 1969-2005
  - Subseries A: Audiocassettes, undated, 1972-2005
    - 28th Annual Seminar: Priorities and Promises, Education for the 21st Century, Cincinnati, OH, 1988 April 15-17 (Box 84:, Folder ACass_132)
      Tapes #1-20, missing #4, 7
    - 29th Annual Seminar: The Child, The World, The Future, 1989 April (Box 83:, Folder ACass_125)
      Tapes #1-44, missing #3-4, 6, 11, 19, 26, 28, 34, 40
    - Day Care, Mary R. Summer, 1989 (Box 105:, Folder ac_172)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd25
    - Heads of School Session, First Annual Summer Seminar, "Communication", Santa Fe, NM, Joseph Procaccini, 1989 July 28 - 30 (Box 88:, Folder ACass_150)
      Tapes #1-7, missing #2, 6
    - Gravel, Maria, 199? Febraury 15 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_80)
    - Winter Regional Seminar: Reaching Out, Montessori in the 1990's, Seattle, WA, 1990 February 15 - 18 (Box 82:, Folder ACass_119)
      Tapes #1-25, missing #6, 9, 11
    - 30th Anniversary: Montessori in Contemporary American Culture, Arlington, VA, 1990 April 25 - 27 (Box 82:, Folder ACass_123)
      Tapes S12, 13A-B, 14S
    - Winter Regional Seminar, Consultation Workshop, 1990 April 25 - 27 (Box 84:, Folder ACass_130)
      Tapes 24A-D
    - 30th Anniversary National Conference: Celebrating Children of the Earth, Washington, D.C., 1990 April 26 - 29 (Box 82-83:, Folder ACass_124)
      Tapes #1-43, missing #10, 21, 29 (labels off)
    - Fall Regional Conference: Education For A New World, West Palm Beach, FL, 1990 October 26 - 28 (Box 82:, Folder ACass_120)
      Tapes #1-28, missing #3, 10, 25-26
    - Fall Regional Seminar, 1991 (Box 82:, Folder ACass_121)
      Tapes #1-16, missing #8
    - Fall regional Seminar, 1991 (Box 89:, Folder ACass_153)
      Tapes #17-30, missing #18, 20, 26
    - 31st Annual Conference, Boston, MA, 1991 April 26 - 28 (Box 82:, Folder ACass_122)
      Tapes #1-44, missing #1-2, 7, 15-16, 20, 26, 30-31 (labels off some tapes)
    - Winter Regional Seminar, Anaheim, CA, 1992 February 13 - 15 (Box 89:, Folder ACass_154)
      Tapes 1A, 1C-D, 2A-D, K1-4, 3A-E, 4B-E, 5A-D, 6A-C, 6E
    - 32nd Annual Seminar, Chicago, IL, 1992 April (Box 87:, Folder ACass_143)
      Tapes #1-48, missing #18
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Princeton, NJ, 1992 October (Box 80:, Folder ACass_115)
      Tapes #1-39, missing #1, 16, 35
    - Winter Regional Seminar, Houston, TX, 1993 February (Box 79:, Folder ACass_112)
      Tapes #1-44, missing #10
    - 33rd Annual Seminar, 1993 April (Box 80:, Folder ACass_113)
      Tapes #1-61, missing #30, 36, 53, 59
    - 33rd Annual Seminar: Keynote Speaker: "The Transformation of the Teacher"/ Nancy McCormick Rambusch, undated (Disk 2006-0230/CD47 R, Box 33:, Folder ACass_58)
      Tape #41
      Access
      Originals not available due to fragility. Use 2006-0230/CD47 R.
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Virginia Beach, VA, 1993 October (Box 80:, Folder ACass_114)
      Tapes #1-32, missing #11-12, 20B, 23
    - Winter Regional Seminar, St. Petersburg, FL, 1994 February (Box 81:, Folder ACass_118)
      Tapes #1-42, missing #27, 40
    - 34th Annual Seminar and symposium, Dearborn, MI, 1994 April (Box 89:, Folder ACass_155)
      Tapes #1-43, missing #20, 26
    - Summer Regional Seminar, Breckenridge, CO, 1994 August (Box 89:, Folder ACass_156)
      Tapes #1-15A
    - Summer Regional Conference, Beckenridge, CO, 1994 August (Box 78:, Folder ACass_102)
      Tapes #15B-29
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Cincinnati,OH, 1994 October (Box 87:, Folder ACass_144)
      Tapes #1-47, missing #11
    - Winter Regional Seminar, New Orleans, LA, 1995 January (Box 86:, Folder ACass_142)
      Tapes #1-62, missing #50
    - Summer Regional Seminar, Honolulu, HI, 1995 August (Box 81:, Folder ACass_116)
      Tapes #1-45, missing #16-17,21, 25B, 29, 35, 38
    - 36th Annual Conference: Hand in Hand, School and Community Working Toward the 21st Century, 1996 (Box 85:, Folder ACass_137)
      Tapes #1-54, missing #4, 12
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Philadelphia, PA, 1996 October (Box 91:, Folder ACass_159)
      Tapes #1-43, missing K1-2, #3, 24, 34
    - Winter Regional Seminar, San Francisco, CA, 1997 January 31 - February 2 (Box 84:, Folder ACass_129)
      Tapes K1, L1, #1-46, missing #8, 12, 17, 41
    - Bermingham, John, 1997 June 26 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_90)
    - Gravel, Douglas, AMS (tape 1-A), 1997 July 2 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_78)
    - Blessington, John, 1997 July 18 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_75-76)
    - Warner, Frederick, 1997 September 20 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_77)
    - Warner, Louise, 1997 September 20 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_89)
    - Drake, Philp, 1997 November 18 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_87)
    - Rambusch, Robert, 1998 February 9 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_91)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd38
    - 38th Annual Conference, Boston, MA, 1998 March (Box 87-88:, Folder ACass_147)
      Tapes K1-4, L1, Rambush lecture, #1-68, missing #12, 16, 20
    - Fall Regional Conference, Tampa, FL, 1998 (Box 59:, Folder ACass_61)
      Tapes K1-3, #1-48, missing #39
    - Winter Regional Seminar, Houston, TX, 1999 (Box 60:, Folder ACass_62)
      Tapes K1-2, #1-55, missing #35
    - 39th Annual Seminar, Cincinnati, OH, 1999 April (Box 61:, Folder ACass_63)
      Tapes K1-3, #1-49
    - 39th Annual Seminar, Cincinnati, OH, 1999 April (Box 62:, Folder ACass_64)
      Tapes #1-2, 50-95, missing #57, 59, 60, 78, 87
    - Accredation Workshop, Dottie Sweet Feldman, 1999 April (Box 62:, Folder ACass_160)
      Tapes A1-4
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Oakland, CA, 1999 October (Box 63:, Folder ACass_65)
      Tapes K1-3, #1-65, missing #8, 9, 11, 23, 47, 55, 58
    - Donahue, Gil Sonja, 1999 November 10 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_83-85)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd39
    - 40th Annual National Seminar, New York, NY, 2000 March (Box 81:, Folder ACass_117)
      Tapes K1-2, R1, F1-4, H1a-b, #1-50, missing #33, 35
    - 40th Annual National Seminar, New York, NY, 2000 March (Box 83-84:, Folder ACass_128)
      Tapes H2-6, F5, C1a-b, #51-85, missing #52, 59, 64
    - Midwest Regional Seminar, Grand Rapids, MI, 2000 July 28 - 30 (Box 68:, Folder ACass_88)
      Tapes K1, K3, A1-7, H1-4, C1, #1-15, 9B-G, 10A-E, missing #4
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Dallas, TX, 2000 October (Box 65:, Folder ACass_67)
      Tapes K1-3, W1a-b, 1-56, missing #4, 16, 29
    - Rosa Packard, 2000 November 29 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_81-82)
    - Teacher Symposium: Public School Track, Fort Lauderdale, FL, 2001 (Box 85:, Folder ACass_135)
      8 Tapes
    - Annual Conference, Chicago, IL, 2001 April 19 - 22 (Box 66-67:, Folder ACass_68-69)
      Tapes K1-3, R1, F1-7, #1-82, missing #6, 43, 54, 60, 65
    - Dunns/ Small, 2001 April 21 (Box 76:, Folder ACass_93-94)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd40
    - Perry, C. and D., 2001 April 21 (Box 76:, Folder ACass_92)
    - Summer Regional Conference, Breckenridge, CO, 2001 (Box 64:, Folder ACass_66)
      Tapes K1-3, #1-43, missing #16, 21B, 35
    - Rasmussen, Patti Tepper, 2002 April 2 (Box 76:, Folder ACass_95-96)
    - Weiss, Bretta, 2002 April 26 (Box 76:, Folder ACass_97-98)
    - 42nd Annual Conference, Crystal City, VA, 2002 April 25 - 28 (Box 69:, Folder ACass_71)
      Tapes K1, K3, R1, 1A-G, 2A, 2C-E, 3A, 3C-M, 4B-J, 5A-D, 5F-G, 6A-E, 7A-I, 7K, 8A-G, 9A-E, 9G, 10A-E
    - Eanes, Michael, 2002 October 30 (Box 76:, Folder ACass_99-100)
    - Fall Regional Seminar, St. Louis, MO, 2002 (Box 78:, Folder ACass_101)
      Tapes K2-3, 1-52, missing #17, 47
    - Fall Regional Seminar, Anaheim, CA, 2003 April 19 - 22 (Box 72:, Folder ACass_74)
      Tapes K1-3, 1A-E, 1G, 2A-B, 2D-G, 3B-G, 4B, 4E-F, 5A-G, 6A-B, 6D-G, 7A-E, C1
    - Annual Conference, Crystal City, VA, 2003 April 25 - 28 (Box 68:, Folder ACass_70)
      Tapes #1-11
    - 43rd Annual National Seminar, Covington, KY, 2003 May (Box 70:, Folder ACass_72)
      Tapes K1-3, R1, F1, 1A-D, 1F-H, 1J-M, 1O, 2A-B, 2D, 2F-I, 2K-N, 3A-I, 3L-M, 4B-D, 4F-K, 5A-J, 5L, 6A-B
    - 43rd Annual National Seminar, Covington, KY, 2003 May (Box 71:, Folder ACass_73)
      Tapes 6C-G, 6J-K, 7A-B, 7D-I, 7K, 8A-F, 8H-Ma, 9A-F, 9H-N, 10A, 10C-G, 10I-N, Fund Development workshop 1-2
    - 44th Annual National Conference, Boston, MA, 2004 April (Box 90-91:, Folder ACass_158)
      Tapes K1-5, F1, 2A-F, 2I, 2L-N, 3B, 3D-E, 3G-N, 4A-H, 4K, 5A-F, 5H-J, 6A-J, 6L-N, 7A-B, D-F, 7H-I, 7K, 7M-N, 8A, 8D-G, 8I-K, 9A-B, 9D-J, 9L-O, 10A-B, 10D-H, 10K-O, 11A-F, 11H-J
    - 44th Annual National Seminar, Boston, MA, 2004 April (Box 87:, Folder ACass_146)
      Tapes 11K-N
    - 45th Annual National Conference, Chicago, IL, 2005 April (Box 89-90:, Folder ACass_157)
      Tapes K1-3, F1a-b, F3-4, F7-10, W1-115, missing W7, W23, W25, W39, W41, W47, W60, W71, W90, W97
    - Joy Starry Turner (Folder 2002-0230.ac29)
  - Subseries B: Audio tapes (Reel to Reel), undated, 1961-1969
    - "A Day at Escuela de Montessori in Redondo Beach, CA", undated (Box 37:, Folder RR_28)
    - Junior Course Overview (Math) Mrs. Margaret Clarke, undated (Box 74:, Folder RR_36)
    - Junior Course Overview: The Teacher Child Environment (Language-Geography) Mrs. Margaret Clarke, undated (Box 74:, Folder RR_37)
    - Reel #8, undated (Box 37:, Folder RR_35)
    - Reel #13, undated (Box 37:, Folder RR_34)
    - "Side 2: Delacato", undated (Box [mold]:, Folder RR_22)
    - Talk by Nancy Rumbush of the Montessori School, undated (Box 75:, Folder RR_45)
    - Unidentified loose tapes (Box 77:, Folder RR_58-59)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 75:, Folder RR_41)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 75:, Folder RR_42)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 77:, Folder RR_55)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 77:, Folder RR_56)
    - Unmarked 7-in. reel, undated (Box 37:, Folder RR_32)
    - Rambusch, undated (Folder RR_76)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd34
    - Unmarked 7-in. reel, undated (Box 37:, Folder RR_33)
    - "Languages"/ Elizabeth Stephenson, 1960 October 18 (Box [mold]:, Folder RR_19)
    - "The Montessori Directress"/ Elizabeth Stephenson, 1960 December 6 (Box 36:, Folder RR_20)
    - illegible [possible course], 1960-1961 (Box 36:, Folder RR_24)
    - "Cinderella," lecture at DePaul University/ Nancy Rambusch, Introduction: Urban Fleege, 1961 October 17 (Box [mold]:, Folder RR_31)
    - Rambusch, Christine, 1962-1964 (Folder RR_64)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd10
    - "Overview of Montessori"/ Lena Gitter, 1962 (Box [mold]:, Folder RR_18)
    - Rambusch, Lou V's class, Collective Disorders, 1962-1964 (Folder RR_67)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd13
    - Nancy McCormick Rambusch, Green Bay, WI, 1962 March (Box 37:, Folder RR_30)
    - Seminar: Nancy Rambusch: Sally Cassidy and Gil Donahue; AMS Organization Meeting, 1962 June 8 (Box 35:, Folder RR_13)
    - "Starting a Class"/ M. E. Stephenson - Delacato and Koegler Seminar, ("Mario"), 1962 June 8 (Box [mold]:, Folder RR_23)
    - "Montessori Classroom", 1962 October 7 (Box 36:, Folder RR_25)
    - "Qualities of the Montessori Teacher," "A Look at Pedagogical Anthropology"/ Nancy McCormick Rambusch, 1962 October 9 (Box 36:, Folder RR_17)
    - Rambusch child development, 1962 October 16-18 (Folder RR_71)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd29
    - Rambusch, 1962 October 11 (Folder RR_74)
    - Dr. McDermott, 1962 October 19 (Folder RR_63)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd9
    - John McDermott, 1962 November 9 (Box 36:, Folder RR_15)
    - Dr. McDermott, 1962 November 9 (Folder RR_61)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd7
    - Nancy Rambusch, 1962 December 2 (Folder RR_29)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd5
    - Role of Creativity in the Learning of the child; and the Image the Teacher has of Herself or Himself in Enhancing Creativity in the Child/Lecture on Handwriting Nancy M. Rambush, 1962 December 12 (Box 74:, Folder RR_39)
    - Dr. McDermott, 1962 November 30 (Folder RR_75)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd33
    - AMS Seminar J. McCauley and Lena Gitter/Dr. McDermott and Dr. Kroeger, 1963 (Box 74:, Folder RR_40)
    - Jo Ann, Lena Gitter PET, Session 4, 1963 January 24 (Folder RR_60)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd6
    - Dr. McDermott, 1963 January 25 (Folder RR_68)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd14
    - AMS Seminar, Nancy M. Rambush, Mr. Stevens, 1963 (Box 74:, Folder RR_38)
    - "Language Development"/ Lena Gitter, 1963 January 26-27 (Box 36:, Folder RR_21)
    - Montessori Seminar Father Hagmaier/Dr. McDermott, 1963 January 27 (Box 75:, Folder RR_43)
    - Language Development Lena Gitter/Simple and Complex analysis chart, 1963 January 27, March 7 (Box 75:, Folder RR_44)
    - "System of Numeration as it relates to early learning experiences"/ Nancy McCormick Rambusch, 1963 January 28 (Box 36:, Folder RR_16)
    - "Starting a Class" and "Afternoon Workshop"/ M. E. Stephenson, 1963 January 30 (Box 36:, Folder RR_26)
    - "Address to Interviewing Representatives of Affiliated Schools," "Preface to a lecture on Pre-Natal, Natal Experience", 1963 January 30 (Box [mold]:, Folder RR_27)
    - Dr. Tibbetts, 1963 March 19 (Folder RR_65)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd11
    - Dr. McDermott, 1963 February 15 (Folder RR_70)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd28
    - Dr. McDermott, 1963 March 29 (Folder RR_72)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd30
    - Panel Rambush, Roger, Tibbet, 1963 August 16 (Box 77:, Folder RR_47)
    - Nancy M. Rambush, 1963 August 16 - 19 (Box 77:, Folder RR_50)
    - Nancy M. Rambush project for children, 1963 August 19 (Box 77:, Folder RR_49)
    - Nancy M. Rambush, 1963 August 22 (Box 77:, Folder RR_46)
    - Nancy M. Rambush, Language AM, 1963 August 28 (Box 77:, Folder RR_48)
    - Nancy M. Rambush--Montessori Theory Lecture, 1963 August 14 (Box 77:, Folder RR_51)
    - Dr. McDermott, 1964 August 12 (Folder RR_69)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd15
    - Training course, Dr. McDermott, 1964 August 14 (Folder RR_66)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd12
    - Dr. McDermott lecture Fairleigh Dickinson University, 1964 August 21 (Folder RR_62)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd8
    - Rambusch, 1964 August 27 (Folder RR_73)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd31
    - AMS Seminar, Chicago, IL, 1969 June 17 - 21
      - "The Montessori Concept of Freedom and Its Implications for the Classroom"/ Paul Czaja, Commentary: Terry Denny, Introduction: John Sullivan (Box 35:, Folder RR_1)
      - "Helping Our Children Actualize Their Potential"/ Joan Beck, Introduction: Virginia Fleege (Box 35:, Folder RR_2)
      - "Visitation Goals and Results"/ Lillian DeVault - "Standards for Student Teaching Sites and Supervisory Personnel"/ Sonja Donahue - "Teacher Training Course Standards"/ Urban H. Fleege (Box 35:, Folder RR_3)
      - "Sex Education," "Development of Sexuality"/Dr. Ann Lucas, Introduction: Jane Bunker (Box 35:, Folder RR_4)
      - "Public Relations"/ John Sullivan - "School-Teacher Relations"/ John Blessington - "Establishing a 6-9 Program"/ Larry Lewis, Modertaor: Otto Bouc (Box 35:, Folder RR_5)
      - "Impact of the City on the Learning Opportunities and Life Styles of Children"/Dr. Albert E. Parr, Commentary: Roberta Meyer Bear, Introduction: Franklin D. Toups (Box 35:, Folder RR_6)
      - Sally Cassidy; Gil Donahue (Box 35:, Folder RR_7)
      - Sally Cassidy, undated (Box 35:, Folder RR_8)
      - Workshop Panel on "Implementing Montessori in the Home" (Box 35:, Folder RR_9)
      - Workshop Panel on "Articulating the Work of the Montessori School with the Efforts of the Home" (Box 35:, Folder RR_10)
      - "Developing a Positive Self-Image in the Child: Implications for Teachers and Parents"/Fleege, Dinkmeyer, Gorman, Introduction: Mrs. W. Loeffler (Box 35:, Folder RR_11)
      - Workshop on "Practical Problems in Organizing a Montessori School"/ T. Calleton, R. Raabe, J. Hennes, Moderator: John Sullivan (Box 35:, Folder RR_12)
    - Nancy M. Rambush, 1969 July 8 - 10 (Box 77:, Folder RR_52-54)
    - AMS Seminar: "Montessori Truth"/Nancy [Rambusch?] - flip side: Dr. Baratz, 1970 June 18 (Box 35:, Folder RR_14)
    - Ben Lee, Third Lecture, 1971 (Box 77:, Folder RR_57)
    - John McDermott and Dr. Tibbetts, 1963 March 8, 22 (Box 77:, Folder RR_77)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd41a-c
    - John McDermott, 1963 March 15 (Box 77:, Folder RR_78)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd42
    - John McDermott, 1962 December 14 (Box 77:, Folder RR_79)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd43a-b
    - John McDermott, undated (Box 77:, Folder RR_80)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd44
    - John McDermott, 1964 August 19 (Box 77:, Folder RR_81)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd45a-b
    - Nancy M. Rambusch, 1963 February 11 and March 6 (Box 77:, Folder RR_82)
      Use copy 2006-0230_cd46a-b
  - Subseries C: Phonograph Records, undated
    - Original master record for Folk Tunes and Music of the Masters Adapted for the Classroom/ Elsie Braun Barnett, undated (Box 38:, Folder LP_1)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd1
    - Commercial copy of Folk Tunes and Music, American Montessori Society Demonstration Record, undated; 2006-0230/LP2; 2 sound discs: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo; 12 in. (Disk 2006-0230/LP2)
  - Subseries D: Compact Discs, undated
    - W.R. Saltzman, Graduation, 1971 (Box 106:, Folder CD_2)
    - Childcare USA, TV program #26, undated (Box 106:, Folder CD_3)
    - Music Workshop (noisy), undated (Box 106:, Folder CD_4)
    - Folk Tunes and Music of the Masters adapted for the Classroom, undated; 2006-0230/CD1 (Disk 2006-0230/CD1)
- Series XXIII: Videocassettes and Films, undated, 1970-1987
  - Subseries A: Videocassettes, undated, 1980, 1982
    - Chelsea Children's Center, undated (Box 39:, Folder VR_3)
    - Cleo and Nancy, undated (Box 39:, Folder VCASS_2)
    - " Jack Blessington,", undated (Box 39:, Folder VCASS_4)
    - Maria Gavel, Doug Gravel and Bretta Weiss, undated (Box 39:, Folder VCASS_5)
    - Nancy Rambusch, undated (Box 39:, Folder VCASS_3)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 38:, Folder VCASS_1)
    - Magnetic tape unmarked, undated (Box 38:, Folder VR_1)
    - Magnetic tape unmarked, undated (Box 38:, Folder VR_2)
    - AMS film, 1980 (Box 39:, Folder VCASS_7)
    - Two Stories on Montessori Seminar Annual Seminar in Memphis, Cynthia Williams, 1982 (Box 39:, Folder VCASS_6)
  - Subseries B: Films, undated
    - 3-in. reel of film with no container or label, undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_14)
    - 5-in reel in can with illegible label, undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_12)
    - 30-second Public Announcement, undated (Box 37:, Folder MP_16)
    - "60 sec. PSA Montessori", undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_9)
    - Education film unmarked, undated (Box 38:, Folder MP_2)
    - "Environmental Exercises", undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_6)
    - "Montessori: 30" (WHBQ-TV 13 Memphis), undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_13)
    - "Montessori, A Demonstration of the Method" (16 mm. color film, reel ? of 2), undated (Box 38:, Folder MP_2)
    - "Montessori: An Education for Life,", undated; 2006-0230/MP1; 1 film reel (ca. 30 min.): sd., col.; 16 mm. (Cassette 2006-0230/VR19 I, Disk Dodd DVD181 R, Reel 2006-0230/MP1)
      Researchers must view the reference copy of the film. Use Dodd DVD 181 R.
      Location of Copies or Alternate Formats
      Film transferred by Northeast Historic Film, November 2012. Betacam SP cassette tape and DVD recorded from archival original print.
    - "Montessori-An Introduction for Parents,", undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_10)
    - Practical life, undated (Box 38:, Folder MP_3)
    - "Thinking, Moving, Learning", undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_11)
    - Ruth Obolensky's Photographic Essay 2, Part I", undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_7)
    - Ruth Obolensky's Photographic Essay (Part II), undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_8)
    - "Sensorial and Playground" ( Ruth Obolensky's Photographic Essay), undated (Box 40a:, Folder MP_5)
    - Sensorial apparatus, undated (Box 38:, Folder MP_4)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 38:, Folder MP_15)
- Series XXIV: Photographs and Slides, undated, 1907-1980
  - Script for "A Day at Escuela de Montessori", undated (Box 40)
  - Index cards with lists of slides, undated (Box 40)
  - Slide tray with script and audiocassette: "Developmental Gymnastics", undated (Box 40b)
  - Montessori Centennial Celebration (II) (Folder PH_2)
  - Original II, undated (Box 40b:, Folder PH_3)
  - Original I, undated (Box 40b:, Folder PH_4)
  - Manhattan Color Labs, undated (Box 40b:, Folder PH_5)
  - Patty Calver--Practical Life Slide, undated (Box 40b:, Folder PH_6)
  - Patty Calver--Duplicate I, undated (Box 40b:, Folder PH_7)
  - Duplicate of Montessor Centennial Celebration, undated (Box 40b:, Folder PH_8)
  - Children at Carousel Nursery School, New York, [color snapshot], undated
  - Children at a Montessori school, [5x7 prints], undated
  - Children at Academy of the Visitation, Saint Louis, Missouri, [b/w snapshots], undated
  - Children, Yellow Springs, [b/w snapshots], 1969
  - Children at Montessori School of Westchester, NY, [8x10 prints], undated
  - Workshop with woodturning lathe, saw-table, [b/w snapshots], undated
  - Children at Keller School, Switzerland, [5x7 prints], undated
  - Child playing with blocks, [8x10 print], undated
  - Students at blackboard, [8x10 print], undated
  - Typical Montessori school set-up, [8x10 prints], undated
  - Children developing language skills, [8x10 prints], undated
  - L&A Wise Memorial Day Care Center, [8x10 prints], undated
  - Children developing mathematical skills, 1968
  - Child playing with blocks, undated
  - Children at prayer, [8x10 print], undated
  - Children listening to a Montessori teacher, [8x10 print], undated
  - Children doing mathematical activities, undated
  - Children involved in instructional activities, undated
  - Unidentified meeting, undated
  - Nancy Rambusch, undated
  - Workshops, AMS Seminar, Grand Hotel, Mackinac Island, Michigan, [8x10 prints], 1973
  - Meeting participants?, [b/w snapshots], 1971 February
  - Unidentified speaker, 1973 August
  - David R. Weinberg [5x7, 2x3 prints], undated
  - Franklin D. Toups, [5x7 print, c.1,2; 5x7 negative], undated
  - Unidentified, [5x7 print], undated
  - Anne McCarrick, St. Joseph Montessori School, Columbus, Ohio, [1.5x2.5 color print, c.1 4x5 b/w prints, c.2, c.3 4x5 negative], undated
  - Eileen Mills, Montessori Children's House, San Mateo, California, [4x5 color print, c.1.; 4x5 b/w print, c.2; 4x5 negative], undated
  - Richard D. Kanakanui, [4x5 print; 4x5 negative ], undated
  - Dort Czewinsky and David Weinberg, [color snapshot], 1975 November
  - Theodore E. Calleton, [5x7 print, c.1, 2; 5x7 negative], undated
  - John P. Blessington, [2x3 color print, b/w snapshot, 5x7 print, 8x10 print], undated
  - Robert H. Johnson, Jr., [8x10 print], undated
  - Goldstein, [color snapshot], undated
  - Giuliani, [color snapshot], undated
  - Shahbaz K. Mallick, [4x5 print, c.1; 5x7 print, c.2-4 5x7 negative], undated
  - James F.Chambliss, [5x7 print; 5x7 negative], undated
  - Sal Messineo, [5x7 print]; [5x7 negative], undated
  - Leon Kunstenar, [8x10 prints], undated
  - AMS Seminar, Philadelphia, [8x10 prints], 1977 June
    - Nancy Rambusch
    - The Mummers, Mariott Hotel
    - David R. Weinberg
    - Opening session
    - Virginia Varga and Oscar C. Christensen
    - The Mummers
  - School in Hong Kong, [5x7 color prints], undated
  - Children at Blessed Trinity Montessori, Ocala, Florida, 1969
  - Principal speakers at the 12th Annual AMS Seminar, Mackinac Island, Michigan, 1973 June 14 - 16
    - Burton L. White, [5x7 prints; 5x7 negative]
    - Dr. Lee Salk, [5x7 prints; 5x7 negative]
  - Sylvia O. Richardson, [5x7 print], undated
  - Charles L. Shedd, [5x7 print], undated
  - Albert H. Gieseke, Villa Montessori, Phoenix, Arizona, [color snapshot], undated
  - Samuel Botto, [color snapshot], undated
  - Carles C. Turner, Villa Montessori, Phoenix, Arizona, [3x4 print], 1976
  - Virginia Varga, Gloria Dei School, Ohio, [5x7 print], undated